A Guide to the 8th Evacuation Hospital 1941-2011
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- Dictabelt records by Dictaphone July 1942-September 1943, Artifacts: 44 red plastic, grooved dictabelts; 4 DVD audio recordings of the 95 recordings on the red dictabelts in boxes 17 and 18 (Box-folder 17-000)
  The belts contain recordings of Byrd Leavell dictating his wartime journal
- Dictabelt records by Dictaphone 1943 September - 1945 November, Artifacts: 51 red, plastic, grooved dictabelts and 5 blue, plastic, grooved dictabelts, 2 CDs (Box-folder 18-000)
  The red belts contain recordings of Byrd Leavell dictating his wartime journal and the blue belts are of Leavell dictating a draft of portions of his book The 8th Evac.
- RUTH BEERY'S UNIFORM 1942-1945, ARTIFACTS: black cloth cap; olive green cloth cap in navy blue cloth pouch; olive green cloth cap; khaki cloth cap; olive green cloth jacket with metal buttons, and 2 Army Nurse Branch Cadesus pins with eagle, the letter "N," and clutch back post attachments, European - African - Middle Eastern campaign medal with 4 stars, Fifth Army patch, 2 U. S. pins, arm patch with five rectangular bars, 2 silver-colored metal bars, and green patch with golden-colored wreath; 2 olive green cloth skirts each with a plastic button and metal zipper; khaki cloth shirt with plastic buttons; olive green cloth pants with metal zipper; olive green cloth shirt with plastic buttons; 3 khaki cloth ties, green cloth pouch with metal zipper;; 6 clutch back post attachments; 63 gold-colored metal, detached enlisted men buttons of varying sizes: twenty-one 5/8 inch, six 3/4 inch, twenty-six 7/8 inch, ten 1 and 1/8 inch; and one officer service cap insignia of gold-colored metal. Enclosed note indicates more of Ruth Beery's uniform in vault (oversize). (Box-folder formerly 19-000, now in Artifacts Collection)
- E. CATO DRASH'S UNIFORM 1942-1945, ARTIFACTS: olive green cloth pants with metal zipper and plastic buttons; 4 olive green cloth caps with gold and black braid, one has gold metal U.S. pin and another has a silver eagle pin; 1 khaki cloth cap; 2 khaki cloth caps with gold and black cord; 1 cloth and leather hat with two gold-colored metal buttons, and one officer service cap insignia of silver-colored metal. Enclosed note indicates more of E. Cato Drash's uniform is in vault (oversize). (Box-folder formerly 20-000, now in Artifacts Collection)
- Washing hair, Marie Galvin and unidentified woman, early Italy 1943-44, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-001)
- soldier having a drink ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-002)
- Nurses and servicemen outside at Anfa Hill, Morocco, tents in background 1943, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.5 x 5 (Box-folder 21-003)
  left to right: Ned Waddell, Betsy Johnson, Kate Robinson, Alice Huffman, Alice Law, Billie Gibson
- Jim Boston and Bea Ramsey approaching jeep to depart on their honeymoon, Italy 1945 August 25, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 21-004)
  M. Cathleene Carter is standing with her back to the camera
- Group photo of former 8th Evac members and family members at reunion 1960, PHOTO 1-B&W 5.75 x 14 (Box-folder 21-005)
- Group photo of former 8th Evac members at reunion 1960, PHOTO 1-B&W 5.75 x 14 (Box-folder 21-006)
- Group photo of former 8th Evac members and family members at reunion 1960, PHOTO 1-B&W 5.75 x 14 (Box-folder 21-007)
- Group photo of former 8th Evac members and family members at reunion 1960, PHOTOS 2-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 21-008)
- Group photo of former 8th Evac members and family members at reunion 1960, PHOTOS 2-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 21-009)
- Group photo of former 8th Evac members at reunion 1960, PHOTOS 2-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 21-010)
- Group photo of former 8th Evac members at reunion 1960, PHOTOS 2-B&W 8 x 10 (Box-folder 21-011)
- Entry gates of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-012)
- Interior hallway of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-013)
- Scene with palm trees at Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-014)
- Interior of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-015)
- Grounds of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-016)
- Bedroom with netting over bed at Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-017)
- Interior of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-018)
- Interior of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-019)
- Library interior of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-020)
- Bedroom with netting over bed at Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-021)
- Library interior of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-022)
- Library interior of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-023)
- Interior of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-024)
- Interior of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-025)
- Interior of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-026)
- Stage of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-027)
- Dining table at Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-028)
- Exterior of building of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-029)
- Exterior of building of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-030)
- Exterior of building of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-031)
- Exterior of building of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-032)
- Exterior of building and gardens of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-033)
- Exterior grounds of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-034)
- Exterior grounds of Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-035)
- Garden at Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-036)
- Palm trees at Villa Malfitano, Palermo, Sicily ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-037)
- Castle by the water 1943 July, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.75 (Box-folder 21-038)
  Notation of back: Castel Falconera, near Licata, Sicily - my first billet in Sicily - Headquarters 1st Engineer Special Brigade
- Residenz fountain with horses, Residenz Square, Salzburg, 1947 June 5, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.75 (Box-folder 21-039)
- View of city of Salzburg 1947 June 5, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.75 (Box-folder 21-040)
- Buildings along the river, Salzburg 1945 August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-041)
- Buildings and bridge in Salzburg 1945 August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-042)
- Mountains, Salzburg 1945 August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-043)
- Bad Ischel, Salzburg 1945 August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-044)
- Bad Ischel, Salzburg 1945 August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-045)
- Lake Garde to Reves tunnel 1945 August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-046)
- City scene 1944 December, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-047)
  Notation of back: Rest camp
- Crowd in Paris 1945 August 24, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-048)
  Notation on back: Paris, night celebration in the street
- Buildings and street in Paris 1945 August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-049)
- Buildings and street in Paris 1945 August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-050)
- Buildings in Paris 1945 August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-051)
- Opera house, Paris 1945 August, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-052)
- Roman Forum, Rome ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-053)
- elaborate front of a building, probably a church ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-054)
- View of a town by water with mountains in the background ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-055)
- Roman forum, the Arch of Septimius Severus, Rome ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-056)
- City buildings ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-057)
- Elaborate structure with statues on top, including a horse ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-058)
- Gardens and elaborate structure with statues on top, including a horse ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-059)
- Water and mountains ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-060)
- Rowboat on water ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-061)
- Camel and donkey with rider ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 5.25 (Box-folder 21-062)
- Street scene ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 5.25 (Box-folder 21-063)
- Corpus Christi pageantry, Isle of Ischia, Italy 1944 Spring, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 4.75 (Box-folder 21-064)
- Road through mountains with trucks ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 6 (Box-folder 21-065)
- Bridge ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 6 (Box-folder 21-066)
- Buildings ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 6 (Box-folder 21-067)
- Ward tents in snow, Pietramala, Italy 1944-45, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 21-068)
- Soldiers at attention in front of tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 21-069)
- Soldiers and nurses at attention in front of tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 21-070)
- Soldiers and nurses at attention ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 21-071)
- Soldiers and nurses at attention ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 21-072)
- First group of 8th Evac nurses ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-073)
- Group in front of tents, Ruth Beery seated in chair on left ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 21-074)
- Operating tent with patient with head wound 1944, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 21-075)
  Dorothy Sandridge is giving anesthesia to the left, Armed Forces Institute of Pathology photo C44-549
- Oxen pulling a cart in front of tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-076)
- Nurses in tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.25 (Box-folder 21-077)
  Left to right: Helen Berkeley, 2 unidentified women, Hilda Franklin, Lelia Cloyd
- Nurses and soldiers at attention ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 21-078)
  Drash is pinning a medal on an unidentified man
- Camp at Goat Hill, 15 miles east of Oran, Algeria 1943 September, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 21-079)
- Staige Blackford ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 1.75 x 2.5 (Box-folder 21-080)
- Marie Galvin in white on her wedding day 1944 April 11, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 21-081)
- McKoan in middle back, Frances Carter is Red Cross worker with basket 1943-44, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-082)
- Left to right: Snavely, Hornbarger, Wiseman ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 21-083)
- Men posed by x-ray sign, man on far right is Harry \Dumbleton ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 3.75 (Box-folder 21-084)
- Group standing, including Elizabeth Wiseman and Drash on far right ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-085)
- Two unidentified men and Jeep decorated with streamers and marked "Just Married" ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 21-086)
- Unidentified man holding picture of a woman and standing next to Ella Gillespie who is holding buckets ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 5.5 (Box-folder 21-087)
- Mess tent tables and benches ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5.25 (Box-folder 21-088)
- Nurses and servicemen at attention ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 4 x 5.75 (Box-folder 21-089)
- Unidentified men in front of tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 21-090)
- Jefferson Day celebration ND, PHOTOS 2-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 21-091)
  Left to right: first woman is Addie Roadcap, Holmboe sitting on first end seat to left, Mulford behind Holmboe. The two kneeling men are Snavely (on left) and Casscells taking photos. Monin is above and slightly to the left of Snavely.
- Kitchen ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.75 (Box-folder 21-092)
- Patient standing by ambulance ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.75 (Box-folder 21-093)
- Building with sign: Le Restaurant Panoramique ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.75 (Box-folder 21-094)
- Building: Le Restaurant Panoramique ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.75 (Box-folder 21-095)
- Servicemen outside tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.75 (Box-folder 21-096)
- Unidentified servicemen standing outside ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 21-097)
- Tents, possibly utility area ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.75 (Box-folder 21-098)
- Tent with sign "Evac Rec" ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.75 (Box-folder 21-099)
- Tents with Le Restaurant Panoramique in background ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.75 (Box-folder 21-100)
- Servicemen standing in front of tents, Le Restaurant Panoramique in background ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.75 (Box-folder 21-101)
- Army vehicles and road by water-filled ditch ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 21-102)
- Unidentified man by tree ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.75 (Box-folder 21-103)
- Unidentified serviceman in front of tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-104)
- Patients, servicemen, and tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3.5 x 5 (Box-folder 21-105)
- Unidentified man sitting on a cot ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-106)
- Unidentified serviceman by tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-107)
- Unidentified serviceman outside tent ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-108)
- Unidentified serviceman standing outside ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 21-109)
- Unidentified woman outside ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 2 x 3 (Box-folder 21-110)
- Three unidentified men standing outside tents ND, PHOTO 1-B&W 1.25 x 1.75 (Box-folder 21-111)
- The Daily Progress, Charlottesville, VA, "8th Hospital Unit Awarded Plaque by War Department" 1945 October 1, newspaper clipping, 1 pg. (Box-folder 21-112)
- "Virginia on War Front" E. Cato Drash ND, newspaper clipping, 1 pg. (Box-folder 21-113)
- Palermo, Sicily, Monte Pellegrino - Castella utveggio 1933, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 22-001)
  Notation on back: Fotocelere di A. Campassi - Terino - Via Marochetti 41 - 1933 X 1
- Casablanca, Morocco, Vue generale aerienne ND, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 22-002)
- Notation on back: 67 Casablanca, Morocco, Boulevard de la Gare ND, Postcard 1-Brown&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 22-003)
- Notation on back: 64 Casablanca, Morocco, Boulevard Gouraud ND, Postcard 1-Brown&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 22-004)
- Palermo, Sicily, Panorama visto da monreale ND, Postcard 1-Brown&Pink 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 22-005)
- Notation on back: Salzburg - Festung und Nonnberg ND, Postcard color 1-3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 22-006)
- Notation on back: Hohensalzburg und Gaisberg von der Richterhohe ND, Postcards 2-color 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 22-007)
- Notation on back: Wien, Rathaus, Nach einem Aquarell von karl Schwetz, Wien ND, Postcard 1-color 4 x 6 (Box-folder 22-008)
- Notation on back: Wien, Staatsoper, Nach einem Aquarell von karl Schwetz, Wien ND, Postcard 1-color 4 x 6 (Box-folder 22-009)
- Caserta - Caserma Generale Sacchi (15 Regg. Fanteria) - Monumento ai Caduti ND, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 22-010)
- Caserta - Viale Carlo III ND, Postcard 1-Brown&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 22-011)
- Caserta - La Reggia vista dall' alto ND, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 22-012)
- Caserta - Giardino Reale - Panorama ND, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 22-013)
- 298 Monreale - Conca D'Oro 1937, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 22-014)
- Lilian Anderson ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.25 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-015)
- Kirkman and Drash holding cups in middle of others in front of tents ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-016)
- Group standing, Kirkman 4th from the left ND, Photo 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 22-017)
- Holmboe standing by sign that says "Commanding Officer, Executive Officer" pre 1945 August 29, Photo 1-color 3.25 x 4.5 (Box-folder 22-018)
- Group of men sitting, Kirkman 2nd from the left 1945 May 8, Photo 1-B&W 3.5 x 4.75 (Box-folder 22-019)
  Notation of back: A "flashlight" photo of a typical evening "in the field" except that this happened on VE day - night. We were having a drink and toasting the gallant lads who cracked the Nazi Super Man myth.
- Eight men standing, Kirkman then Blackford on far left, Long holding bottle ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-020)
  Notation of back: We have our less serious moments too. This is at a division clearing station up front; Blackford, Barker Long and I were showing Turner, from the SGO, a glimpse of the war from a safe distance.
- Group inside, some sitting on sofa ND, Photo 1-B&W 3.5 x 4.5 (Box-folder 22-021)
  Left to right: Kirkman, Reyer, Carmaak, Long, Sturgeon; second row: Generals Martin, Davis, Stayer, 300th QH
- Ralph Camardella ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 22-022)
- Group of six standing outside pre 1945 march 19, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 22-023)
  Notation of back: ?, General MC Stayer, General Joe I. Martin, The Brazilian Surgeon General and assistant Major Buchanan LWK [Kirkman]; Above does not appear to be in order left to right. Martin is 2nd from left and Stayer is 3rd from left, Kirkman is to the far right.
- Beach umbrellas along Castiglioncello shoreline 1944 August, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 4.5 (Box-folder 22-024)
  Notation on back: Fifth Army Medical Dept. Rest Center at Castiglioncello, between Cecina and Leghorn, August 1944
- Men having drinks in front of a tent ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.25 (Box-folder 22-025)
  Notation on back: A most informal pose "cocktails before the showers" at the 170th [Evac] near Treviso. Jack Donaguy, Bang (John O.) McNeel, LWK [Kirkman]. The guy peeking from behind the tent door is [ ] French, one of the [ ] original O'Reilly [ ]
- Kirkman in front of basketball court ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.25 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-026)
  Notation on back: An early AM shot showing the basketball court we fashioned beneath the rugged peak called Mount Beni at Pietramala, Italy, on Highway 65 halfway between Florence and Bologna
- General Clark (2nd man from left) and King George VI (4th man from left) reviewing nurses 1944 July-August, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 22-027)
- Facing camera: Kirkman on far right, Holmboe second to the right ND, Photos 2-B&W 2.5 x 3.75 (Box-folder 22-028)
- Head shot of unidentified service woman ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-029)
  Notation of back: Casson Studio, 1305 Connecticut Ave, Washington D.C.
- Head shot of unidentified service woman ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.25 (Box-folder 22-030)
  Notation of back includes: Studio of Hear's Inc. Springfield Mo.
- Unidentified service woman standing outside city building ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-031)
- Road through mountains with trucks ND, Photo 1-B&W 4 x 6 (Box-folder 22-032)
- Kirkman standing next to a vehicle pre 1945 October 18, Photo 1-color 3.25 x 5 (Box-folder 22-033)
- Two servicemen standing outside building, Kirkman on left ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-034)
- Two unidentified servicemen standing by army car in front of tents ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-035)
- Pietramala, Italy from mountainside ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 22-036)
- Unidentified men at outdoor eating area, two men in chef's hats ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-037)
- Boxes and lumber ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.25 x 3.25 (Box-folder 22-038)
- Unidentified man standing by truck ND, Photo 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.75 (Box-folder 22-039)
- Truck and tents ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.25 x 3.25 (Box-folder 22-040)
- Men with chef's hats carrying table ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-041)
- Kirkman and unidentified woman sitting on bed ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-042)
- Kirkman ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-043)
- Unidentified young adults, two women, three men on mountain outcrop ND, Photo 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.75 (Box-folder 22-044)
  Two men are wearing sweaters with big initial H and all wearing hiking boots
- Unidentified young adults in mountains, two men, one woman ND, Photo 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.75 (Box-folder 22-045)
- Army camp, evidently partially deconstructed 8th Evac at Pietramala, Italy ND, Photo 1-B&W 4 x 6 (Box-folder 22-046)
- Army camp, evidently partially deconstructed 8th Evac at Pietramala, Italy ND, Photo 1-B&W 4 x 6 (Box-folder 22-047)
- Tents, man and woman on badminton court ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-048)
- Ward 1 building ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-049)
- Tents ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.25 x 3.25 (Box-folder 22-050)
- Four unidentified men, one a serviceman holding a dog ND, Photo 1-B&W 3 x 4.5 (Box-folder 22-051)
- Two servicemen [Kirkman far right?] standing in front of 8th Evac Hospital sign ND, Photos 4-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 22-052)
- Head shot of Robert Weller ND, Photo 1-B&W 3.5 x 5 (Box-folder 22-053)
- UVA History of the Health Sciences Club: An Evening of Reminiscences on the 50th Anniversary of the University of Virginia's Evacuation Hospital Unit in World War II 1995 January 11, Flyer 1 pg. (Box-folder 22-054)
- The Daily Progress: Medical history buffs remember hospital's role in World War II 1995 January 16, Newspaper clipping 1 pg., Photocopy of newspaper clipping 1 pg. (Box-folder 22-055)
- The Daily Progress, Region and State section: Medical history buffs remember hospital's role in World War II 1995 January 16, Newspaper clipping 6 pp. (Box-folder 22-056)
- Introduction of Distinguished Veterans by Charles Thornsvard 1995 January 11, TD with AN, 2 pp. (Box-folder 22-057)
- Notation of back: Randell Luscomb [Randal Luscombe] holding flag of America, first in Blackwater Centennial Parade, May 30, 1987 1987 May 30, Photo 1-color 3.5 x 4.25 (Box-folder 22-058)
- Randal Luscombe carrying the U.S. flag in Blackwater Centennial Parade 1987 May 30, Photo 1-color 3.5 x 5 (Box-folder 22-059)
- Sketches by Randal Luscombe of the new tent frame he helped make 2000, Drawings 2 pp. (Box-folder 22-060)
- Note and drawing from Randal and Berneice Luscombe describing walking iron for broken leg 2000 October 7, 1 Drawing, 1 ANS, 3 pp. (Box-folder 22-061)
- Randal and Berneice Luscombe 2000 February 22, Photo 1-color 4.5 x 6 (Box-folder 22-062)
- Letter from Melvin Shaffer to Joan E. Klein enclosing newspaper clipping from the Richmond Times Dispatch: Pilot plans airport's future 1997 March 18, 1 TLS 1 pg., 1 newspaper clipping 2 pp. (Box-folder 22-063)
- Bulletin of the University of Virginia Medical School and Hospital: articles on the 8th Evac 1942-1975, 5 photocopies TD 16 pp. (Box-folder 22-064)
  Articles include: Medical Department Organizes Evacuation Hospital Unit No. 8 for Foreign Service, Eighth Evacuation Hospital Trained in Active Duty during Carolina Maneuvers, News of Our Eighth Evacuation Hospital Now Established Overseas Five Months, Brief History of the Eighth Evacuation Hospital, The 8th Evac-Thirty Years Later
- Bulletin of the University of Virginia Medical School and Hospital: articles on the 8th Evac 1942-1975, 5 photocopies TD 15 pp. (Box-folder 22-065)
- Operating room of the *th Evac 1945 February 8, Photo 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 22-066)
  Photo shows changes made in operating light to eliminate cumbersome legs and braces formerly used. Armed Forces Institute of Pathology 5 MM-45-1812
- Five members of the 8th Evac holding an Italian flag pre 1980, Photos 1-B&W 8 x 10, 1-B&W 7.5 x 9.5 mounted, 1 AN (Box-folder 22-067)
  Left to right: Cato Drash, John Guerrant, Ruth Beery, Norman Thornton, Byrd Leavell with Italian flag from Casablanca. Photo taken at an 8th Evac reunion in Charlottesville. Flag was later returned to Italy.
- Group photo of 8th Evac reunion, Alumni Hall, Charlottesville ND, Photo 1-B&W 7.5 x 9.5 mounted (Box-folder 22-068)
- Two unidentified men, probably attendees of 8th Evac reunion ND, Photo 1-B&W 7.5 x 9.5 mounted (Box-folder 22-069)
- Group photo of 8th Evac reunion, Farmington, Charlottesville, VA 1950 August, Photo 1-B&W 8 x 10, 1 AN (Box-folder 22-070)
- Letter from McLemore Birdsong to Fellows and group photo of the Department of Pediatrics and former residents 1960 November 11, Photo 1-B&W 8 x 10 mounted, 1 TDS 1 pg., 1 sticker (Box-folder 22-071)